Jiaxu (Joshua) Luo

NEW YORK, NY <u>jl4298@columbia.edu</u> (917)399-7490 https://www.linkedin.com/in/jiaxuluo https://github.com/Joshuacourse

SUMMARY

A lifelong learner with experience in data science research, product development, and big data engineering on cloud architecture. Problem solver with research stamina, a can-do attitude, and cross-functional influencing skills. My career goal is to become a data scientist (engineer) with strong engineering skills to scale (with cloud technologies) analytical solutions to business problems.

EDUCATION

Udacity - Data Engineering Nanodegree Program	In Progress
Udacity - Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree Program	Aug 2019
NYC Data Science Academy New York, NY - A three month, full-time program on data science	Sept 2016
Columbia University New York, NY - MS, Chemical Engineering (Data Science Concentration)	Dec 2015
Wuhan University of Technology Wuhan, China - BS, Material Science and Engineering	Jun 2014

EXPERIENCE

Broker Genius | New York, NY (startup team with two members)

Oct 2018 - Present

Data Scientist

Tools: Python, BigQuery, AI platform, Machine Learning, Container

- Devised methodology in distinguishing fake sales from sales and implemented engineering solutions for automated modeling retraining, data validation, and hourly batch prediction (the company's first ML model).
- Create production-ready data warehouses with scheduler and automate data pipelines and educate stakeholders in Sales, Support, Pricing, and Finance to utilize enriched data to inform data-driven decision making.

Business Intelligence Engineer

May 2017 - Present

Tools: Python, R, Shiny, Crontab, Hive, Airflow, ElasticSearch, Tableau

- ♦ Designed, built, deployed, and keep monitoring 20+ production-ready reporting pipelines for the company's \$2 billion ticket inventory management, 200+ clients' activities monitoring, 40+ pricers productivity evaluation, etc.
- ♦ Reduced 80% operating costs and improved accounting accuracy for the financial department by designing and developing an automated invoicing, delivery, and recording system on monthly billing and accounting of 200+ clients.
- ◆ Validate new ideas by researching data integrity and developing fast prototypes with end-to-end solutions.

Beijing Genomics Institute | Shenzhen, China (Remote part-time)

Machine learning consultant

Feb 2017 - May 2017

♦ Researched, validated and implemented risk prediction modeling techniques for the detection of HPV infection based on genotyping data, which will increase early detection of cervical cancer for adult women.

PROJECTS

Customer Segmentation for Arvato Financial Services

Tools: Python, AWS, Machine Learning (PCA, Clustering, Lightgbm)

Aug 2019 - Oct 2019

- ♦ Characterized customers segment of using demographics information and compare against that of the general population, identifying the parts of the which that best describe the core customer base of a company for subsequent target marketing.
- ♦ Built supervised machine learning model that predicts whether or not each individual will respond to the campaign and made predictions on the campaign data as part of a Kaggle Competition. (Udacity Capstone with Kaggle Leaderboard #9)

Yelp Review Mining - (Team leader of four members)

Tools: R, Shiny, Tableau, Machine Learning (Topic Modeling, Xgboost)

Sept 2016

- ♦ Extracted hidden topics and menus from Yelp customers reviews (positive & negative) for each type of restaurant by LDA(Latent Dirichlet allocation) to shed insights into the business operation of different restaurant types.
- ♦ Detected the key business operational metrics with predictive modeling for highly-rated restaurants and built up an application to deliver actionable insights. (App)

SKILLS

Certification:	GCP Professional Data Engineer Data Science Bootcamp Machine Learning Engineer
Language & Tools:	Python R SQL Spark Hive Airflow ElasticSearch Git Tableau Looker Linux H2O
Machine Learning:	Clustering PCA GLM Xgboost Random Forest Neutral Network NLP
Cloud:	Google Cloud Platforms (BigQuery, AI Platform, Cloud Storage, Dataflow)
	AWS (Sagemaker, S3, Redshift, Lambda Fucntion) Docker Kubernetes